Gunda is a documentary film directed by Viktor Kossakovsky.
A glimpse into the raw and simple power of nature through encounters with farm animals:
the eponymous Gunda, a mother pig; two cows, and a one-legged chicken.
Gunda (transl.
Goon) is a 1998 Indian Hindi-language action film written by
Bashir Babbar and directed by Kanti Shah.
Starring Mithun Chakraborty, Mukesh Rishi and Shakti Kapoor, the film was produced by Anil Singh and the music was composed by Anand Raj
Anand.The narrative revolves around a coolie who vows to exact revenge upon a crime lord and his cronies after they kill his loved ones.
The film was released on 4 September 1998.
Over time, the film has gained a cult following, selling
over 2,000 VCD copies at a single outlet.
It also received a limited re-release in 2018.
The same year, actor Deepak Shirke who played politician Bachubhai,
revealed that the film was pitched to him without a script.
The film explores themes of farm, pig, nature, vegan, no dialogue.